Sebastian Ghafafian

www.linkedin.com/in/sebastian-ghafafian/

Summary

Data scientist and mechanical engineer with four years of experience at the intersection of industry and academia. Creative problem solver with an eye for detail. Collaborative and fast learner able to tackle new challenges with a positive attitude.

Experience

Structural Engineer for Composite Materials

TPI Composites Germany GmbH

01/2021 - 08/2023

Parlin, Germany

- Design and execution of large-scale experimental composite sandwich testing using project and equipment management skills
- Development, deployment and code maintenance via Git of 3D tool for visualization of structural analyses in Python
- Effective communication with partners from research institutions throughout Europe within the "Reliablade" project
- Ownership of project-oriented Python packages for composite stiffness and failure analyses

Research Associate

Federal Institute for Materials Research and Testing (BAM)

11/2019 - 12/2020

Page Berlin, Germany

- Statistical safety and reliability assessment of composite overwrapped pressure vessels
- Improvement of pressure vessel regulations for Hydrogen and Fuel Cell Vehicles within the European research project "TAHYA" using Monte-Carlo Simulations (MCS)
- Improved computational efficiency of MCS in Matlab by over 200%

Intern for Composite Materials and Manufacturing

Institute for the Research and Development of Sports Equipment (FES)

10/2016 - 09/2018

PBerlin, Germany

- Creation of precise manufacturing specifications and their communication to directors and manufacturing technicians
- · Manufacturing and feasibility study with novel production techniques for composite materials

Teaching Assistant

Technical University Berlin

10/2016 - 09/2018 PBerlin, Germany

• Focus on presenting complex subject matters to different audiences for five different courses

Skills Numpy Scikit-Learn Neural Networks with PyTorch **Pandas** Webscraping with Beautiful Soup SQL Dashboards with Dash Plotly Seaborn Principal Component Analysis

Education

MicroMaster in Statistics and Data Science

Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MITx via edX)

05/2022 - 10/2023

- · Built strong foundation in statistics and probabilistic
- · In-depth study and application of unsupervised and supervised learning algorithms

M.Sc. Mechanical **GPA** 3.8 / 4.0 **Engineering** Technical University of Berlin (TUB)

10/2018 - 08/2019

• Master's Thesis research: Probabilistic influence on material properties of fiber reinforced plastics

B.Sc. Mechanical **GPA** 3.2 / 4.0Engineering

Technical University of Berlin (TUB)

10/2013 - 05/2018

<u>Languages</u>

German	Native	••••
English	Proficient	••••0
Armenian	Beginner	●●000
French	Beginner	•0000

Involvement & Certifications



FaSTUBe (TUB Formula Student Racing Team)

Head of Fiber Reinforced Plastics Manufacturing Team



Quality Engineer – Green Belt Applied Data Science for Quality and Reliability Engineering



IBM Data Science Professional Certificate

Hands-on skills of Data Science methodology including Data Wrangling, Visualization, Machine Learning and SQL